JACOB LEROY GARLICK

6121 Ammons Street, Arvada, CO 80004 | 970-749-0868 | <u>jacobgarlick@msn.com</u> References are available upon request



PERSONAL TRAITS

Friendly, professional, punctual and self-motivated with excellent technical, written and oral skill sets to compliment experience. Able to adapt to new settings and work environments in timely manner. Driven by understanding of personal responsibilities and how those affect the prime organization and key stakeholders at large. Always striving to improve education, communication and intersectionality between various disciplines to address complex issues.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

October 2018

- Present

Energy Efficiency Coordinator, Department of Public Health and Environment | City & County of Denver [Denver, CO]

- Assist in administration of Energize Denver's Benchmarking Program, which benchmarks all energy use in buildings
 within Denver over 25,000 sq.ft. and reports annually on energy use while promoting energy efficiency and cost
 saving measures through creative economic and development partnerships as well as education for owners and
 building managers
- Assist in policy development per draft rules and regulations for Denver's Green Building Ordinance, which requires new and existing buildings to consider one of several compliance pathways for greener and more energy efficient, climate friendly buildings in the Denver
- · Provide support to Climate Action Team on number of new initiatives around the city, and provide extensive research on other domestic and international programs for energy conservation, energy decarbonization, and new technologies being developed and deployed to address climate change issues

November 2017 – July 2018

Interim Department Director, Department of Tribal Planning | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Coordinated with BIA Awarding Official to recreate process of drawdowns from Interim time in 2016 for an expedited closeout of two still active but complete projects and helped facilitate the reimbursement of monies due to the Tribe that had not yet been paid out
- Helped facilitate a major transportation project between the Tribe and State of Colorado (both CDOT and CPW), including the solicitation of federal funds from annual processes and the submission, through the Tribe's Contracts
 Grants Division, for a one time increase of funds available in the form of a BUILD Grant to supplement available project resources
- · Managed over \$12 million in federal transportation grants and other tribal resources, providing guidance to Tribal Administration on appropriate use of funds and coordinating with BIA officials to ensure federal compliance on use of funds

September 2017 – November 2017

Project Manager, Department of Construction & Project Management | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Continued duties from apprenticeship into full department position with additional authority over Tribal construction projects
- Took on additional responsibilities while other department Project Manager was away, including becoming main point of contact between the Tribe and outside contractors for active construction work on several road and housing projects
- · Continued to improve occupation specific skills focused on elements of engineering, design and construction with large scale projects including residential, commercial and infrastructure work

August 2016 – September 2017 Apprentice Project Manager, Department of Construction & Project Management | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Shifted focus from long term planning documents and strategies to pre-design, engineering and construction phases of projects identified from planning documents
- Trained extensively in construction management skills and tools, including preparation of RFPs for engineering, design and construction phases, review and authorization of pay applications, preparation of various contracts, change orders, work directives, contractor selection, ASIs and RFIs, ROW and NEPA coordination and review with applicable local and federal agencies
- · Continued to be integral team member on Tribe's first major housing development in decades, including construction management of 23 new home lots, 25 townhome rentals with all related infrastructure, a resident park, new road off a major Colorado highway, cul-de-sac extension and coordination with all government and private entities as work progressed

April 2016 – August 2016

Interim Department Director, Department of Tribal Planning | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- Took control of several million dollars in active P.L. 93-638 federal road contracts with the Bureau of Indian Affairs, Department of Transportation Southwest Region
- · Began the Tribe's updated Comprehensive Land Use Plan Update from previous 2005 document, a long-term planning document and Tribal Council approved tool used to designate best use allocation and plan for infrastructure and capital project expansion in Tribal Campus and surrounding area
- · Oversaw completion and acceptance from Tribal Council of the Tribe's updated Long-Range Transportation Plan and first iteration of Tribal Traffic Safety Plan, both vital transportation planning documents used to justify annual federal funding allocations as well as solicit additional federal, state and local grant funding

September 2015 – April 2016

Tribal Planning Internship, Department of Tribal Planning | Southern Ute Indian Tribe [Ignacio, CO]

- · Learned various aspects of urban and rural planning for transportation, housing, commercial, and safety issues on the Southern Ute Indian Reservation
- · Gained an understanding about the unique aspects of working in a Tribal setting with specific entities of the Federal Government geared towards Native American tribes
- · Began to work closely with Department of Housing and Department of Construction & Project Management on several projects, acquiring unique skills and on-site educational tools from each

EDUCATION

Spring 2020

Master of Arts – Political Science, University of Colorado – Denver [Denver, CO]

{In Progress}

Spring 2014

Bachelor of Arts - Political Science, Fort Lewis College [Durango, CO]

Minor – History, Fort Lewis College [Durango, CO]

ADDITIONAL SKILLS

Technology

Highly proficient with Microsoft Office and its components; Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Project, etc. Proficient with other text-oriented software i.e. Notepad, Notepad++ and Adobe Software. Experience with CRM software including SalesForce and Accela. Training in ArcGIS, AutoCAD, and Project Management software (ProLog).

Languages

English AAAAA Spanish AAA

HOBBIES

In my free time I enjoy as much time outdoors as possible, constantly looking for the next opportunity to take my Tributary HD raft out for some white-water adventure. I also enjoy camping, snowboarding, ultimate and frisbee golfing, traveling, some quality time in the gym, leisurely reading, attending live music and engaging in outdoor and adventure photography.